<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the Lord Deputy General, and General Governour of Ireland. A declaration concerning the pay, and clothing of the army. Tyrconnel, Whereas we are given to understand, that his Majesties forces, especially the foot, are in a miserable condition for want of thier due weekly subsistence; ...</title>
            <author>Ireland. Lord Deputy (1687-1689 : Tyrconnel)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 7KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B24685</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99886342</idno>
  <idno type="VID">186601</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2248538504</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing I373</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide C.21.f.12[29]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide G.6022[28]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R225863</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99886342</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99886342e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B24685)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 186601)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C5:2[29]; C23:1[28])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the Lord Deputy General, and General Governour of Ireland. A declaration concerning the pay, and clothing of the army. Tyrconnel, Whereas we are given to understand, that his Majesties forces, especially the foot, are in a miserable condition for want of thier due weekly subsistence; ...</title>
                  <author>Ireland. Lord Deputy (1687-1689 : Tyrconnel)</author>
                  <author>Tyrconnel, Richard Talbot, Earl of, 1630-1691.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>3 sheets ([3] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Andr. Crook and Sam. Helsham assigns of Benjamin Tooke, printer to the King's most excellent Majesty; and are to be sold by Andrew Crook at his Majesties printing-house on Ormonde-Key, and by Samuel Helsham at the Colledge-Arms in Castle-Street.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Dublin, :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1687.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Title from caption and opening lines of text.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon.</note>
                  <note>"Given at His Majesties Castle of Dublin this 29th day of April, in the year 1687.".</note>
                  <note>Arms 186.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="geographic_name">Ireland --  Armed forces --  Appropriations and expenditures --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Ireland --  History --  1660-1688 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="declaration">
            <pb facs="tcp:186601:1"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>English coat of arms, circa 1687</figDesc>
                  <p>HONI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</p>
                  <p>DIEV ET MON DROIT</p>
               </figure>
            </head>
            <head>BY THE Lord Deputy General, AND General Governour of IRELAND.</head>
            <head type="sub">A DECLARATION Concerning the Pay, and Clothing of the Army.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>TYRCONNEL,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>HEREAS We are given to Understand, That His Majesties Forces, especially the <hi>Foot,</hi> are in a mise<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable Condition for want of their due weekly sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sistence; and that His Majesties <hi>End,</hi> the <hi>Preserva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion</hi> of the <hi>Peace</hi> of this His Kingdom, for which He is at the Charge of maintaining an Army, is in danger to be Defeated, by the many Disorders and Abuses thence like to arise: We have thought fit, for prevention of these and such like Mischiefs, to look into very narrowly, and examine with all pos<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sible exactness, the present condition of the Army; and having sent for several Clothiers and Trades<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men, and brought down, as low as might be, the Prices and Rates of every thing, using <hi>Our</hi> utmost <hi>Care</hi> and Endeavors for the Souldiers subsistence, and to make them pleased with the Service; and having computed their present
<pb facs="tcp:186601:2"/>Debts for Old Clothes, to the Disbanded Men, and the deductions for New Clothes, their Swords and Belts; <hi>We</hi> find their circumstances will not per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mit a greater allowance for the subsistence of a Private Centinel in the Regi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of Guards in <hi>Dublin,</hi> whose Pay is eight pence a day, than two shillings six pence a week; Nor for the subsistence of a Private Centinel in the other Regiments, whose Pay is six pence a day, than one shilling and eleven pence half-penny a week, from the last of <hi>March</hi> to the last of <hi>December</hi> next. <hi>We</hi> do therefore Declare and Command, that every private Centinel in the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giment of Guards, shall weekly receive in and for that time, two shillings six pence for subsistence. Every private Centinel in the other Regiments, one shilling and eleven pence half-penny. Every Sergeant six shillings; and every Corporal four shillings, which We will take care shall be lodg'd in their re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>spective Officers hands, that the men may be duly and punctually paid. And that from and after the said last day of <hi>December</hi> next, by which time all their Debts will be fully paid, every private Souldier in the Regiment of Guards, shall receive weekly after the Rate of six pence a day, three shillings six pence; and in the other Regiments, after the Rate of four pence a day, two shillings four pence. Every Sergeant seven shillings; and every Corpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral four shillings eight pence clear of all deductions whatever. And We do likewise declare, that the Army shall be Clothed once in 18 Months; and for that time every Man is to receive a Coat and Breeches lin'd, and after ten Months to be turn'd without any Charge; an Hat, four pair of Shooes, three pair of Stockins, three Shirts, three Cravats, and a Sash, all very good in their kind, according to the patterns of the several particulars shewn and lodg'd with us.</p>
            <p>And to the end we may understand the true state of the Army, and see how every man has been paid for the time he has serv'd, We do hereby straightly Charge and Require all Collonels, or, in their absence, the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mandants of every Regiment of Horse, Foot, and Dragoons in the Army, forthwith to call together the Respective Captains and Officers, and take an account of every individual mans Pay, Clothing delivered, subsistence paid, and all manner of deductions, from the last of <hi>March</hi> 1686, to the first of <hi>April</hi> 1687; and transmit to <hi>Us</hi> that account, Sign'd by the several Captains and Officers, and Countersign'd by the Collonels or Commandants.</p>
            <p>And We do also Publish and Declare, that as We have resolv'd, no labour and care, on <hi>Our</hi> part, shall be wanting to make this Army useful, and to give the Officers all due Encouragement and Countenance; so, on the other hand, <hi>We</hi> have determined not to suffer any hardships to be put upon the private Souldiers; of whom, as We have been credibly inform'd, many late<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly in-listed, have been frequently turn'd off, without being accounted with, or paid, for the time of their service. We do therefore hereby strictly Require and Command, that for the future no man be dismiss'd, except by <hi>Our</hi> particular Order, but at the Musters, the Cause express'd and approv'd by the Collonel, or Officer Commanding in Chief, in the Respective Garrisons, and a new man at the same time produc'd and in-listed; and that every man Dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charg'd, be first accounted with, and fully paid off to a farthing.</p>
            <p>And <hi>We</hi> do likewise Will and Require, that the Collonels, Captains, and Subalterns of the Respective Regiments, do take special Care, that their men keep and wear their Clothes and Linnen neat and clean.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:186601:3"/>
            <p>And lastly, that all Disorders and Irregularities may be Rectified and Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dress'd, and all grounds of Complaint, for the future, taken away; We do hereby straightly Charge and Command, that this <hi>Our Declaration</hi> be within ten days from the date of it, Read and Published at the Head of every Troop and Company, and afterwards posted up, and fix'd in the Market, and other publick places, of the several Garrisons within this Kingdom; to the <hi>End,</hi> the private men may know what they are to expect: and that none may pretend ignorance of these <hi>Our</hi> Orders and Directions, which are to be carefully and punctually observ'd by all persons Concern'd; upon the pain of Cashiering, and <hi>Our</hi> utmost Displeasure.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>Given at His Majesties Castle of</hi> Dublin <date>
                     <hi>this</hi> 29th <hi>day of</hi> April, <hi>in the Year</hi> 1687.</date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="license" subtype="order_to_print">
            <p>
               <hi>By his Excellencies Command.</hi>
            </p>
            <closer>
               <signed>THO. SHERIDAN.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>DUBLIN, Printed by <hi>Andr. Crook</hi> and <hi>Sam. Helsham</hi> Assigns of <hi>Benjamin Tooke,</hi> Printer to the King's Most Excellent Majesty; And are to be Sold by <hi>Andrew Crook</hi> at His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jesties Printing-House on <hi>Ormonde-Key,</hi> and by <hi>Samuel Helsham</hi> at the <hi>Colledge-Arms</hi> in <hi>Castle-Street.</hi> 1687.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>